A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1946-1947
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1946-1947
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.551 I & II
This collection consists of 11,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 1955 February 3.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
Organization
SUB-SERIES I: General Files, 1946 Boxes 1-10
SUB-SERIES II: General Files, 1947 Boxes 11-22
Contents List
- Sub-series I: General Files, 1946
  - "A" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board 1946 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board--General Correspondence 1946 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board--Investments 1946 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board--Meetings 1946 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board--Treasurer 1946 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Fund--Class Managers 1946 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Fund Council 1946 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Fund--Gifts 1946 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Office 1946 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education 1946 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education--Bulletins 1946 (Box 1)
  - Ancient Languages 1946 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1946 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions 1946 (Box 1)
  - Art and Architecture--purchase of Bass Otis portrait of Jefferson 1946 (Box 1)
  - Art Commission 1946 (Box 1)
  - Association of American Colleges 1946 (Box 1)
  - Astronomy--presentation of a trophy by the McCormick's to Mr. Mitchell 1946 (Box 1)
  - Athletics 1946 (Box 1)
  - "B" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 1)
  - Biology 1946 (Box 1)
  - Biology--Blandy Farm 1946 (Box 1)
  - Biology--Mountain Lake 1946 (Box 1)
  - Buildings and Grounds--General 1946 (Box 1)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Commons 1946 (Box 1)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Electricity 1946 (Box 1)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Buses 1946 (Box 1)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Costs 1946 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Engineering 1946 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Faculty Housing 1946 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Fayerweather Hall (proposed addition) 1946 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Federal Public Housing Authority 1946 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Housing Bills and Printed Material 1946 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Progress Reports 1946 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Project Management Plans 1946 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: War Assets Administration 1946 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Women Students 1946 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Woodrow Wilson Hospital Dormitories 1946 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Fuel 1946 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Gas 1946 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Hospital 1946 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Rotunda 1946 (Box 2)
  - Building Program--Architects and Engineers 1946 (Box 2)
  - Building Program--Cafeteria and Dining Hall 1946 (Box 2)
  - Building Program--General 1946 (Box 2)
  - Building Program--Library 1946 (Box 2)
  - Building Program--Medical Buildings 1946 (Box 2)
  - Building Program--Men's Dormitories 1946 (Box 2)
  - Building Program--Naval Armory 1946 (Box 2)
  - Building Program--Site Plans 1946 (Box 2)
  - Building Program--Student Activities Building 1946 (Box 2)
  - Building Program--Women's Dormitory 1946 (Box 2)
  - Bursar's Office--General 1946 (Box 2)
  - Bursar's Office--Fellowships and Students' Assistants 1946 (Box 2)
  - Byrd, Senator H. F.--routine correspondence 1946 (Box 2)
  - "C" Miscellaneous--(under "Crowell" an enclosure from Eleanor Roosevelt, re: her educational philosophy) 1946 (Box 3)
  - Carnegie Corporation 1946 (Box 3)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching--General File 1946 (Box 3)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching--Minutes of Meetings 1946 (Box 3)
  - Catalogues 1946 (Box 3)
  - Chemistry --(Prof. Yoe reports on the first effects of the atomic bomb) 1946 (Box 3)
  - Church Society for College Work 1946 (Box 3)
  - Commerce and Economics Department 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Academic Legislation 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Administrative 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Board of Visitors 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Building (local) 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Curriculum 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Extension Advisory 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Faculty Housing 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Fund Drive 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Medical 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Overseas Schools 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Preparation of Students for Government Service 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Presidents' of Ladies 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Public Occasions 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Publications (Student Council on Topics) 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Research 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Schedule and Class Room Assignments 1946 (Box 3)
  - Committee--Univ. of Va. Press 1946 (Box 3)
  - Commons 1946 (Box 3)
  - Convocation 1946 (Box 3)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 4)
  - Dean Ferguson 1946 (Box 4)
  - Dean Finley 1946 (Box 4)
  - Dean Hollingsworth 1946 (Box 4)
  - Dean Lewis (contains a paper on the future of the University) 1946 (Box 4)
  - Dean Newman 1946 (Box 4)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 4)
  - Education--General 1946 (Box 4)
  - Education--Graduate 1946 (Box 4)
  - Education--Nursing 1946 (Box 4)
  - Engineering 1946 (Box 4)
  - English 1946 (Box 4)
  - Extension Division 1946 (Box 4)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 4)
  - Faculty (1) 1946 (Box 4)
  - Faculty (2) 1946 (Box 4)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--General 1946 (Box 4)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Bayly-Tiffany 1946 (Box 4)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Rhodes 1946 (Box 4)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Ryan 1946 (Box 4)
  - Finals 1946 (Box 4)
  - Forestry, dept. of 1946 (Box 4)
  - Forestry (Seward Forest), dept. of 1946 (Box 4)
  - Foreign Affairs (Stettinius to/from Pres.) 1946 (Box 5)
  - Forms and Form Letters 1946 (Box 5)
  - Founder's Day 1946 (Box 5)
  - Fraternities 1946 (Box 5)
  - Fund Raising--General 1946 (Box 5)
  - John Price Jones Corporation (fund-raising) 1946 (Box 5)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 5)
  - General Education Board 1946 (Box 5)
  - Geography--Dept. of 1946 (Box 5)
  - Geology, Dept. of 1946 (Box 5)
  - Gifts to the University 1946 (Box 5)
  - Governor's Office 1946 (Box 5)
  - Graduate Dept. 1946 (Box 5)
  - "H" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 5)
  - History 1946 (Box 6)
  - History Commission--World War II 1946 (Box 6)
  - Institute of Public Affairs 1946 (Box 6)
  - Institute of International Education 1946 (Box 6)
  - Insurance 1946 (Box 6)
  - Invitations to be Represented 1946 (Box 6)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 6)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 6)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 6)
  - Law Department 1946 (Box 6)
  - Lectures--General 1946 (Box 6)
  - Lectures--William H. White Foundation 1946 (Box 6)
  - Legal Papers--(W. A. Perkins, atty) 1946 (Box 6)
  - Legislative Program 1946 (Box 6)
  - Library 1946 (Box 6)
  - Library, Board of Alderman 1946 (Box 6)
  - Library--McGregor Library (dedication of room, a series of biographical sketches of the curators included) 1946 (Box 6)
  - Library--Taylor Room 1946 (Box 6)
  - "M" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 7)
  - Madison Hall 1946 (Box 7)
  - Mary Washington College 1946 (Box 7)
  - McIntire Fund 1946 (Box 7)
  - Medical Department 1946 (Box 7)
  - Medical Department--Compensation 1946 (Box 7)
  - Medical Department--Hospital 1946 (Box 7)
  - Medical Department--Nursing School 1946 (Box 7)
  - Medical Department--Student Health 1946 (Box 7)
  - Medical Department--Ward Patients 1946 (Box 7)
  - Memorial Service 1946 (Box 7)
  - Monroe, James--Memorial Foundation 1946 (Box 7)
  - Music--Department of 1946 (Box 7)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 7)
  - National Association of State Universities 1946 (Box 7)
  - National Association of State Universities--Separate State Universities 1946 (Box 7)
  - National Education Association 1946 (Box 7)
  - National Science Foundation 1946 (Box 7)
  - Naval ROTC 1946 (Box 7)
  - Naval ROTC--Printed and Mimeographed Communications 1946 (Box 8)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 8)
  - "P" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 8)
  - Personnel 1946 (Box 8)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1946 (Box 8)
  - Philosophy 1946 (Box 8)
  - Physical Education 1946 (Box 8)
  - Physics 1946 (Box 8)
  - Political Science 1946 (Box 8)
  - Post-War Education Committee 1946 (Box 8)
  - Psychology 1946 (Box 8)
  - Public Administration--Bureau of 1946 (Box 8)
  - Publications 1946 (Box 8)
  - Questionnaires 1946 (Box 8)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 8)
  - Recommendation, Letters of 1946 (Box 8)
  - Requisitions 1946 (Box 8)
  - Research--Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1946 (Box 8)
  - Research--General 1946 (Box 8)
  - Research--Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1946 (Box 8)
  - Research--League of Virginia Counties--County Government Clinic 1946 (Box 8)
  - Research--Richmond University Center 1946 (Box 8)
  - Research--Romance Languages 1946 (Box 8)
  - Research--Rural Social Economics 1946 (Box 8)
  - "S" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 9)
  - Senate (University) 1946 (Box 9)
  - Sigma Xi 1946 (Box 9)
  - Sociology 1946 (Box 9)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools 1946 (Box 9)
  - Southern University Conference 1946 (Box 9)
  - Speech and Drama 1946 (Box 9)
  - State Board of Education 1946 (Box 9)
  - Statistics 1946 (Box 9)
  - Summer Session 1946 (Box 9)
  - Surplus Property 1946 (Box 9)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 9)
  - Taylor, Mrs. R. C. 1946 (Box 9)
  - Tunstall, R. B.--Member, Alumni Board of Trustees 1946 (Box 9)
  - U. S. Military Academy 1946 (Box 9)
  - U. S. Office of Education 1946 (Box 9)
  - University Press 1946 (Box 9)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 9)
  - Veterans 1946 (Box 10)
  - Virginia Education Association 1946 (Box 10)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--Correspondence 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--Mr. Anderson 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--Judge Barksdale 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--Mr. Black 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--Mr. Carrington 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--Dr. Emmett 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--Mr. Garnett 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--Mr. Gay 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--Mr. Goolrick 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--Mr. Mears 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--Mr. Stettinius 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--Dr. Trout 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--Mrs. Wailes 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--Mr. Lewis C. Williams 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--R. Gray Williams 1946 (Box 10)
  - Visitors--Mrs. Willis 1946 (Box 10)
  - "W" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 10)
  - Woodrow Wilson Birthplace Foundation 1946 (Box 10)
  - "X--Y--Z" Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 10)
- Sub-series II: General Files, 1947
  - "A" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 11)
  - Alumni Fund, Class Managers, Bulletin 1947 (Box 11)
  - Alumni Fund--Gifts 1947 (Box 11)
  - Alumni Office 1947 (Box 11)
  - American Council on Education 1947 (Box 11)
  - American Council on Education--Printed and Mimeographed Bulletins 1947 (Box 11)
  - Ancient Languages 1947 (Box 11)
  - Annual Reports 1947 (Box 11)
  - Applications for Positions 1947 (Box 11)
  - Army ROTC--General 1947 (Box 11)
  - Army ROTC--Medical 1947 (Box 11)
  - Art and Architecture 1947 (Box 11)
  - Art Commission 1947 (Box 11)
  - Association of American Colleges 1947 (Box 11)
  - Association of American Universities 1947 (Box 11)
  - Astronomy 1947 (Box 11)
  - Athletics 1947 (Box 11)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1947 (Box 11)
  - "B" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 11)
  - Bicentennial Committee--Bedford 1947 (Box 12)
  - Biology 1947 (Box 12)
  - Biology--Blandy Farm 1947 (Box 12)
  - Biology--Mountain Lake 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: General 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Busses 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Copeley Hill--Activities 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Costs 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Education Building--Temporary Academical Building 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Faculty Housing 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Fuel 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Plumbing 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Roads 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Federal Public Housing 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing: Progress Reports: FPHA 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Temporary Buildings: Engineering 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Fuel 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Hospital 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Laundry 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Law Department 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Library 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Rotunda 1947 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Water 1947 (Box 12)
  - Building Program--University Press 1947 (Box 12)
  - Bursar--Fellowships and Assistantships 1947 (Box 12)
  - Bursar--General 1947 (Box 12)
  - Byrd, Senator H. F. 1947 (Box 12)
  - "C" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 12)
  - Catalogues 1947 (Box 12)
  - Chemistry Department 1947 (Box 12)
  - Church Society for College Work 1947 (Box 12)
  - Commerce and Economics Department 1947 (Box 13)
  - Committee--Administrative 1947 (Box 13)
  - Committee--Board of Visitors 1947 (Box 13)
  - Committee--Bookstore 1947 (Box 13)
  - Committee--Citizens on Displaced Persons 1947 (Box 13)
  - Committee--Faculty Housing 1947 (Box 13)
  - Committee--Inauguration 1947 (Box 13)
  - Committee--Liberal Arts 1947 (Box 13)
  - Committee--Local Building 1947 (Box 13)
  - Committee--Overseas Schools 1947 (Box 13)
  - Committee--Public Occasions 1947 (Box 13)
  - Committee--Publications 1947 (Box 13)
  - Committee--Research 1947 (Box 13)
  - Committee--Schedule and Class Room Assignments 1947 (Box 13)
  - Commons 1947 (Box 13)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 13)
  - Darden, C. W. 1947 (Box 13)
  - Dean Ferguson 1947 (Box 13)
  - Dean Finley 1947 (Box 13)
  - Dean Hollingsworth 1947 (Box 13)
  - Dean Lewis 1947 (Box 13)
  - Dean Newman 1947 (Box 13)
  - Dean Rushton 1947 (Box 14)
  - Development Fund 1947 (Box 14)
  - Development Fund--John P. Jones Corporation 1947 (Box 14)
  - DuPont Trust 1947 (Box 14)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 14)
  - Education--General 1947 (Box 14)
  - Education, Graduate 1947 (Box 14)
  - Education--Nursing 1947 (Box 14)
  - Endowment: Alumni Board--Contingent Fund 1947 (Box 14)
  - Endowment: Alumni Board--General Correspondence 1947 (Box 14)
  - Endowment: Alumni Board: Investments 1947 (Box 14)
  - Endowment: Alumni Board: Treasurer 1947 (Box 14)
  - Engineering 1947 (Box 14)
  - Engineering--Department Surplus Property Requests 1947 (Box 14)
  - English 1947 (Box 14)
  - Extension Division 1947 (Box 15)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 15)
  - Faculty 1947 (Box 15)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships 1947 (Box 15)
  - Finals 1947 (Box 15)
  - Foreign Affairs (1) 1947 (Box 15)
  - Foreign Affairs (2) 1947 (Box 15)
  - Forestry 1947 (Box 16)
  - Forestry (Seward Forest) 1947 (Box 16)
  - Forms and Form Letters 1947 (Box 16)
  - Founder's Day 1947 (Box 16)
  - Fraternities 1947 (Box 16)
  - Fraternities--S.P.E. Case 1947 (Box 16)
  - Friends of the University 1947 (Box 16)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 16)
  - General Education Board 1947 (Box 16)
  - Geography 1947 (Box 16)
  - Geology 1947 (Box 16)
  - Germanic Languages 1947 (Box 16)
  - Gifts to the University 1947 (Box 16)
  - Government Contracts--Air Material Command 1947 (Box 16)
  - Governor's Office 1947 (Box 16)
  - Graduate Dept. 1947 (Box 16)
  - "H" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 16)
  - History 1947 (Box 16)
  - History Commission--World War II 1947 (Box 16)
  - Honor System 1947 (Box 16)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 17)
  - Inauguration Exercises 1947 (Box 17)
  - Institute of International Education 1947 (Box 17)
  - Institute of Public Affairs 1947 (Box 17)
  - Insurance 1947 (Box 17)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 17)
  - Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1947 (Box 17)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 17)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 17)
  - Law Department 1947 (Box 17)
  - Lectures 1947 (Box 17)
  - Legal Matters 1947 (Box 17)
  - Library 1947 (Box 18)
  - Library, Board of Alderman 1947 (Box 18)
  - Library--McGregor Library 1947 (Box 18)
  - Library--Taylor Room 1947 (Box 18)
  - Loan Funds 1947 (Box 18)
  - "M" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 18)
  - Madison Hall 1947 (Box 18)
  - Marine Corps 1947 (Box 18)
  - Mary Washington College 1947 (Box 18)
  - Mathematics 1947 (Box 18)
  - McIntire Fund 1947 (Box 19)
  - Medical Department--General 1947 (Box 19)
  - Medical Department--Hospital 1947 (Box 19)
  - Medical Department--Medical Compensation 1947 (Box 19)
  - Medical Department--Ward Patient Reports 1947 (Box 19)
  - Music 1947 (Box 19)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 19)
  - National Association of State Universities 1947 (Box 19)
  - National Education Association 1947 (Box 19)
  - National Science Foundation 1947 (Box 19)
  - Naval Research 1947 (Box 19)
  - Naval ROTC 1947 (Box 19)
  - Navy--Bureau of Ordnance 1947 (Box 19)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 19)
  - "P" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 20)
  - Personnel 1947 (Box 20)
  - Personnel and Placement Office 1947 (Box 20)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1947 (Box 20)
  - Philosophy 1947 (Box 20)
  - Physical Education 1947 (Box 20)
  - Physics 1947 (Box 20)
  - Political Science 1947 (Box 20)
  - Psychology 1947 (Box 20)
  - Public Administration--Bureau of 1947 (Box 20)
  - Publications and Clippings 1947 (Box 20)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 20)
  - Questionnaires 1947 (Box 20)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 20)
  - Radio--WUVA 1947 (Box 20)
  - Religion 1947 (Box 20)
  - Requisitions 1947 (Box 20)
  - Research--Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1947 (Box 20)
  - Research--Council (National) 1947 (Box 20)
  - Research--Economics 1947 (Box 20)
  - Research--General 1947 (Box 20)
  - Research--Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1947 (Box 20)
  - Research--President's Scientific Board 1947 (Box 20)
  - Research--Richmond University Center (1) 1947 (Box 20)
  - Research--Richmond University Center (2) 1947 (Box 20)
  - Romance Languages 1947 (Box 21)
  - Rural Social Economics 1947 (Box 21)
  - "S" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 21)
  - Senate (University) 1947 (Box 21)
  - Sigma Xi 1947 (Box 21)
  - Sociology 1947 (Box 21)
  - Southern University Conference 1947 (Box 21)
  - Speech and Drama 1947 (Box 21)
  - State Board of Education 1947 (Box 21)
  - Student Affairs 1947 (Box 21)
  - Student Health 1947 (Box 21)
  - Sullivan Award 1947 (Box 21)
  - Summer Session 1947 (Box 21)
  - Surplus Property 1947 (Box 21)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 21)
  - Tunstall, R. B. 1947 (Box 21)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 21)
  - University Press 1947 (Box 21)
  - U. S. Office of Education 1947 (Box 21)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 21)
  - Veterans 1947 (Box 21)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1947 (Box 21)
  - Virginia Education Association 1947 (Box 21)
  - Virginia Music Festival 1947 (Box 21)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1947 (Box 21)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce 1947 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Correspondence 1947 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Mr. Anderson 1947 (Box 22)
  - Visitors--Judge Barksdale 1947 (Box 22)
  - Visitors--Mr. Black 1947 (Box 22)
  - Visitors--Senator Bustard 1947 (Box 22)
  - Visitors--Mr. Carrington 1947 (Box 22)
  - Visitors--Mr. Garnett 1947 (Box 22)
  - Visitors--Mr. Gay 1947 (Box 22)
  - Visitors--Mr. Mears 1947 (Box 22)
  - Visitors--Mr. Stettinius 1947 (Box 22)
  - Visitors--Dr. Trout 1947 (Box 22)
  - Visitors--Mrs. Wailes 1947 (Box 22)
  - Visitors--Mrs. Willis 1947 (Box 22)
  - "W" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 22)
  - War Department 1947 (Box 22)
  - Woodrow Wilson Birthplace Foundation 1947 (Box 22)
  - "X--Y--Z" Miscellaneous 1947 (Box 22)